# **Kevin Patrick Westropp**

kevinwestropp@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/kevinpatrickwestropp

https://www.kevinpatrickwestropp.com

# **Summary**

Kevin is an experienced leader in the software engineering space. He has knowledge that spans across the full stack spectrum with an enhanced focus on front-end design and functionality. He has extensive knowledge in migrating monolithic legacy applications to cloud based microservices, writing new SQL scripts for database schema changes, developing new API endpoints as well as designing new UI's with the most recent front end frameworks and tools. He is an avid learner and enjoys working on new technical and creative projects. He welcomes opportunities to teach and lead others.

# **Experience**

### Software Engineering Team Lead

**Tipico** 

Feb 2022 - Present (11 months +)

Tools & Technology: React, Redux, Typescript, JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, EJS, Mixpanel, GTM, Docker, Kubernetes

Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Leading UX Development team for main sportsbook application
- Coordinating project requirements with stakeholders, product owners, developers, designers and analysts
- Mentoring other developers in expanding programming skills and methodologies
- Building out new UX designs that elevate the User Experience across sportsbook and related applications (i.e. portal & casino)
- Reviewing front end designs and code development to ensure quality standards
- Partnering with Quality Assurance Engineers to expand the robustness of the testing suite of tools and ensure regressions are consistent and include minimal issues for customers
- Working with the Infrastructure team to enhance the CICD pipeline
- Consulting on engineering hiring process to improve talent acquisition
- Working on team capacity planning with Product Management
- Performance monitoring and investigating performance degradation

# **B** Lead Front-End Engineer

**Brinks Home** 

Oct 2020 - Feb 2022 (1 year 5 months)

Tools & Technology: HTML, CSS, Sass, Bootstrap, JavaScript, TypeScript, Vue.js, NuxtJS, Webpack, Contentful, jQuery, Ruby on Rails, Spree, Hubspot, Google Tag Manager, Google Analytics, Jira, Github, Heroku

Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Leading the UX Development team for all marketing related activities
- Coordinating project requirements between stakeholders, developers, consultants, designers and analysts
- Mentoring other developers in expanding UX skills and methodologies
- Building out new UX designs that streamline and elevate the user experience

- Partnering with IT teams to build out infrastructure and workflows for automation of customer lifecycles
- Reviewing front end designs and code development to ensure quality standards
- Promoting performance improvements across different tech stacks
- Technical Point of contact for new UX rebranding efforts
- Production/DevOps Manager for all front-end code changes
- Performing code reviews for all front-end code changes
- Cloud architect, utilizing AWS, Heroku, Git and other Saas applications to host and maintain the brinkshome.com domain along with subdomains
- Managing analytics tracking of user interactions on site and GTM tag maintenance

### Senior Front-End Engineer

#### **Brinks Home**

Nov 2018 - Oct 2020 (2 years)

Tools & Technology: HTML, CSS, Sass, Bootstrap, JavaScript, TypeScript, Vue.js, NuxtJS, Webpack, Contentful, jQuery, Ruby on Rails, Spree, Hubspot, Google Tag Manager, Google Analytics, Jira, Github, Heroku

Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Building out front end website components in vue + html + css + javascript/typescript
- Migrate legacy jQuery code to vue based implementation
- Assisted in setting up and guiding the content authoring solution for marketing, plus helping to define the philosophy around it
- Facilitated the migration of legacy Ruby on Rails platforms to new static web platform powered by Nuxt.js, Contentful and Netlify
- Helped to architect the custom content modeling integration with the front end system using Contentful, Nuxt.js and Netlify
- Review code to ensure high quality of standards
- Work with UX designers to translate designs into functional front end code/markup
- Diagnose and fix bugs across the technical stack
- Mentor and guide other developers in front end development
- Manage projects from ideation through implementation
- Be brand and UI ambassador to other organization development teams



## Senior UI Developer, Senior Consultant

#### **TransUnion**

May 2018 - Nov 2018 (7 months)

Tools & Technology: HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, Webpack, Web Components, Polymer

Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Building new consumer marketing web pages leveraging best in class development techniques
- Improving UI designs and optimizing front-end code
- Focused on performance improvements and optimizations on all TU websites
- Help to implement process improvements and optimized development workflows
- Helping team integrating Agile methodology into existing workflows
- Mentoring other developers by reviewing code and providing guidance to high level designs
- Product Owner for site wide CMS solution

#### Senior Front End Developer, Front End Development Consultant

#### Accenture

Jul 2017 - May 2018 (11 months)

Tools & Technology: HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, Angular, Node.js, Express.js, Azure, AWS Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Working with clients to build out new single page web applications in AngularJS.
- Reviewing code from both external and internal developers to ensure high quality of product and standards.
- Leveraging knowledge of web standards and best practices to help optimize new projects.

### Software Development Engineer II

### Egencia

Jun 2016 - Jul 2017 (1 year 2 months)

Tools & Technology: HTML, CSS, LESS, JavaScript, jQuery, Backbone.js, Handlebars.js, Mocha, Selenium, C++, Java, Spring Boot, Maven, AWS

Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Using agile methodology for development of new Egencia Global Home Page.
- Developing new Fusion (Java Spring) Global Home Page to replace legacy C++ application.
- Leveraging knowledge of Backbone.js, Handlebars and ECMAscript 2016 to implement new front end design for Global Home Page.
- Writing new backend Java Services for development of new client side application.
- Helping to expand on Automation and CICD for faster iteration of features and increasing robustness.

# Software Engineer

#### kCura

Aug 2014 - May 2016 (1 year 10 months)

Tools & Technology: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, .NET, C#, SQL, Angular.js, C++, ASP.NET, Visual Basic, LINQ

Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Developed across full software stack to expand software functionality and features. Wrote new and refactoring C++, C#, Visual Basic, JavaScript, jQuery and SQL code for feature development.
- Wrote new and re-factored C++, C#, Visual Basic, JavaScript, jQuery and SQL code for feature development.
- Leveraged knowledge of MVC, COM, CLR, WebForms, AngularJS, ASP.NET and other technologies to extend and implement functionality.
- Used agile methodology for development life-cycle along side team of less than ten.
- Helped develop UI data visualization widgets with AngularJS, D3.js and C3.js for analytics review.
- Designed endpoints and logic for PDF printing framework to allow for new mass save as pdf option as part of recent software release.
- Re-factored and extended processing software to handle MS Office Field Codes when imaging documents to provide clients with multiple options for output.
- Implemented new UI framework which leverages AngularJS to provide a more robust and feature rich experience for Relativity users.

# savvo

#### Software Developer Intern

Savvo Digital Sommelier Solutions

Feb 2014 - May 2014 (4 months)

Tools & Technology: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C#, .NET, jQuery

Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Update front-end design and functionality of main ASP.NET web application.
- Refactor code and program new designs in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jquery and C#.

# Product Design and QA Intern

#### **TransUnion**

Jun 2013 - Sep 2013 (4 months)

Tools & Technology: iOS, Objective-C, Swift, HTML, CSS, Perl, JavaScript, Java Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Developed an iPhone application for internal server process monitoring and tracking.
- Updated and added functionality for backend web monitoring applications written in JavaScript, HTML
- Tested and wrote documentation for roll-out of proprietary content delivery network (CDN) to use with international websites.



### IT Operations Assistant

ZS

Oct 2012 - May 2013 (8 months)

Tools & Technology: MS Office Suite, Inventory Management Systems,

Responsibilities & Achievements:

- First Point of Contact for Technical Support of Software and Hardware Issues.
- Assisted users with software and systems questions on a daily basis.
- Setup and configured cell phones, laptops, iPads and other hardware.
- Supported IT department initiatives, including roll-outs and hardware updates.

# Litigation Project Assistant

Kirkland & Ellis

May 2011 - May 2012 (1 year 1 month)

Tools & Technology: MS Office Suite, Relativity, Document Management Systems

Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Edited and proofed legal correspondence for court memorandum and briefs.
- Organized and tracked proceedings across databases (Autonomy & Relativity).
- Researched and prepared documentation for attorney team review.
- Coordinated projects for streamlining into larger team work-flow.

# **S** Production Assistant

IES Abroad

Jun 2010 - Apr 2011 (11 months)

Tools & Technology: MS Office Suite

Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Cataloged inventory of marketing brochures, education catalogs and business reports.
- Maintained high-speed Cannon and HP printers, fax machines and copiers.
- Processed and managed outgoing & incoming mail, packages and marketing materials.

#### **Education**

#### **Free Code Camp**

Full Stack Web Development Certification, Computer Software Engineering 2016 - 2016

# DePaul University

Master of Science (M.S.), Computer Science 2012 - 2014

# College of Lake County

Continuing Professional Development, Computer Programming 2010 - 2012

# University of Iowa

Bachelor of Arts, English, Mass Communications 2004 - 2008

## **Lake Forest High School**

High School Diploma, General 2000 - 2004

# **Licenses & Certifications**

Functional Programming Principles in Scala - Coursera Course Certificates 97TXQQEJET

- The Data Scientist's Toolbox Coursera
- Relativity Certified Administrator (RCA) kCura
- **Web Application Architectures** Coursera Course Certificates 5RGSBNCPRD
- Learn Java Course Codecademy
- Learn AngularJS 1.X Course Codecademy

#### Skills

Bootstrap • Nuxt.js • HubSpot • Google Tag Manager • Google Analytics • Jira • Heroku • Contentful • Redux.js • Front-End Development